{
    "questions":[
        {
            "id":"1",
            "question":"Who is considered the first computer programmer?",
            "options":[
                "Alan Turing",
                "Grace Hopper",
                "Ada Lovelace",
                "Charles Baddage"
              ],
            "answer":"Ada Lovelace"
        },
        {
            "id":"2",
            "question":"Which programming language was the first to be used in commercial application ?",
            "options":["Python", "COBOL", "Ruby", "Fortran"],
            "answer":"COBOL"
        },
        {
            "id":"3",
            "question":"Which of the following is the first high-level programming language?",
            "options":["Java", "Fortran", "Python", "C++"],
            "answer":"Fortran"
        },
        {
            "id":"4",
            "question":"Who developed java progreamming language?",
            "options":[
                "James Gosling",
                "Dennis Ritchie",
                "Tim Berners-lee",
                "Guido Van Rossum "
              ],
            "answer":"Dennis Ritchie"
        },
        {
            "id":"5",
            "question":"Which company originally developed the SQL language? ",
            "options":["Google", "IBM", "Miscrosoft", "Oracle"],
            "answer":"IBM"
        },
        {
            "id":"6",
            "question":"Which language was the predecessor to javascript? ",
            "options":["LiveScript", "Perl", "Ruby", "Python"],
            "answer":"LiveScript"
        },
        {
            "id":"7",
            "question":"What was the primary purpose of the pascal programmming language when it was created? ",
            "options":[
                "Game develpoment",
                "Teaching programming",
                "Artificial Inteligence",
                "Web development"
              ],
            "answer":"Teaching programming"
        },
        {
            "id":"8",
            "question":"Which language is known for its use in developing enterprise-level applications particularly banking and financial systems",
            "options":["Java", "COBOL", "Python", "Pascal"],
            "answer":"Java"
        },
        {
            "id":"9",
            "question":"Which of the following was the first Object-oriented Programming language?",
            "options":["Smalltalk", "Simula", "Java", "Lisp"],
            "answer":"Simula"
        },
        {
            "id":"10",
            "question":"Who invented the World Wide Web and the Html language ?",
            "options":["Larry Page", "Alan Turing", "Tim Berners-lee", "Bill Gates"],
            "answer":"Tim Berners-lee"
        },
        {
            "id":"11",
            "question":"What was the primary purpose of creating SQL?",
            "options":[
                "Web development",
                "Managing and querying relational database",
                "Operating system",
                "Ganning"
              ],
            "answer":"Managing and querying relational database"
        },
        {
            "id":"12",
            "question":"Which language is known for its use in mobile application development for andriod?",
            "options":["objective-c", "Kotlin", "swift", "c++"],
            "answer":"Kotlin"
        },
        {
            "id":"13",
            "question":"Who developed the python programming language?",
            "options":[
                "Linus Torvalds",
                "Larry Wall",
                "Guido Van Rossum",
                "James Gosling"
              ],
            "answer":"Guido Van Rossum"
        },
        {
            "id":"14",
            "question":"Which year was PHP first released",
            "options":["1999", "1995", "2000", "1989"],
            "answer":"1995"
        },
        {
            "id":"15",
            "question":"Which programming language was developed specifically for Artifical Inteligence reasearch? ",
            "options":["Java", "c++", "Lisp", "PHP"],
            "answer":"Lisp"
        }
    ]
}